Adam Black

ablack@fastmail.net 0401 868 343

Profile

Highly motivated software engineer with a passion for developing code and solving problems.

Tertiary qualified with a double degree in Telecommunications and Software Engineering and solid professional experience in VB .NET, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and SQL. Completed a 12 week Coursera course on Programming Languages by Dan Grossman covering functional programming concepts using Standard ML and Racket.

Highly competent in Windows, various Linux distributions and UNIX (FreeBSD) with experience configuring various network services including Asterisk.

Excellent verbal and written communication skills and a good team worker with a positive work ethic towards completing tasks within time and to specification.

Willingness to adopt good practices and suggest improvements.

Skills

- Languages: Python, VB .NET, JavaScript
- Frameworks: MVC 5, Entity Framework 6, jQuery
- DBMS: MS SQL Server, Firebird, SQLite
- Editors: Vim, Visual Studio, Eclipse
- VCS: GIT, Subversion
- Server Applications: Apache, BIND, Samba, Buildbot, Asterisk, IIS
- OS: Linux, Unix, OS X, Windows

Experience

IRESS, Melbourne, VIC

Aug 2012 - present

Research Software Developer for one of the leading suppliers of innovative technology solutions for the financial markets, wealth management, and mortgage sectors.

Responsibilities:

- Design and implement features in XPLAN, a financial planning software written in Python.
- Primary developer and maintainer of VB .NET web application used to input superannuation, pension and investment platform provider research data.
- Provide technical support to research analysts.
- · Administer TeamCity builds.

Deliverables:

- Migrated legacy Visual Basic 6 desktop application to Visual Basic .NET web application.
- Managed some complex data migration issues.
- Incorporated Entity Framework 6 into product to improve data access code.
- Introduced MVC5 into application and migrate some poorly written WebForms code into MVC.

Daintree Networks, Scoresby, VIC

Feb 2010 to July 2012

QA Automation Engineer for the market leader in smart building control.

Responsibilities:

• Lead the design and development of a Python-based test automation system.

- Test wireless embedded (ZigBee) platform.
- Debug and analyse transactions in a ZigBee network.
- Measure network performance using JMeter.
- Linux network and services administration: BIND, dhcp3-server, Apache, Samba, Buildbot
- Black box testing, white box testing, and defect investigation.
- Design test plans and test cases.
- Work in an agile environment.

Deliverables:

- Increased the automated test coverage by implementing the required infrastructure and test cases.
- Developed analysis tools used by the marketing team to scope hardware requirements for customer deployments.
- Developed a library for simulating various Modbus power meters using modbus-tk.
- Created a custom Linux installer to streamline the deployment of core product.

Centre for Advanced Internet Architectures.

Feb 2007 - Jan 2008

Swinburne University of Technology Hawthorn, VIC Research Assistant (Industry Based Learning)

- Analysed the network traffic characteristics of various multi-player game engines using py-libpcap.
- Created a Wireshark plugin in C for dissecting VTun packets.
- Measured the power fluctuations in consumer ADSL modems as a function of network traffic.
- Used a Dummynet bridge to introduce latency and jitter between hosts.

Education

Swinburne University of Technology

2010

B.Eng - Telecommunications and Internet Technology / B.Sci - Computer Science and Software Engineering

Awards:

- First class honors in Bachelor of Engineering.
- Faculty of ICT award for the most outstanding final year student in 2010 in the B.Eng Telecommunications and Internet Technology / B.Sci Computer Science and Software Engineering).
- Ericsson Award for the highest achieving student in Broadband Multimedia Networks.
- Australia Arrow Award for the highest achieving student in Software Engineering Project B.
- Highest achieving student in Communication Information Theory.

Interests

- Squash
- Weight training and fitness
- Woodworking
- Cycling

References

Available upon request.